<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Daggers &amp; Bow</string>

    <string name="splash">Daggers and Bow</string>
    <string name="author">Author: Alireza Sani</string>
    <string name="app_dev">App dev: Hamid Sani</string>
    <string name="company_name">Company: A&amp;H</string>
    <string name="company_logo">Company Logo</string>
    <string name="new_game_button">New Journey!</string>
    <string name="continue_button">Continue</string>
    <string name="overview_button">Journey Overview</string>
    <string name="achievements_button">Achievements</string>
    <string name="day_night_mode">Day/Night Mode</string>


    <string name="chapter_1">The end and the beginning &#8230;</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_1">The end and the beginning</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_1t">The wind had spread the horrid smell, permeating through the compound.
        It smelled of death and decay. Joth slowly opened his eyes. First the world was blurry but soon his eyes got used to the dark surroundings.
        He tried to sit up however a searing pain in his side almost made him scream.
        A simple touch later and Joth’s worst fears became reality.
        As luck would have it no vital organs on his side seemed damaged as the armor had done its job and the stab to Joth’s side seemed shallow.
        The bad news was that the wound was bleeding a small but steady stream of blood.
        There was no telling how long he was bleeding though the blood collected in his breastplate had scarcely touched the ground.\n\n

        If Joth was to make his way down the mountain and into a local village for medical attention then he needed to act now.
        From the feel of the wound and the fact that it was from a dagger Joth knew that he needed professional help from a doctor or an alchemist.
        Ideally both. From the looks of this place Joth knew that the compound was fully sacked and he left to die in the rubbles. Then there was the problem of Elain, his sister.
        Joth had a suspicion that the attack on the compound was half motivated by putting down his Grod Vim clan of assassins and sweetened by the idea that the attackers could get their hands on Elain. After all, Elain was special.\n\n

        But Joth had no time to be thinking of her. He saw her being dragged and yet Elain’s value was known to her captors.
        Joth had to save her but there was no point in being reckless seeing as her life was not in danger. If Joth were to die here it would scarcely help Elain’s odds.
        Joth needed to patch up and make his way to town to gather reinforcements before even thinking of breaking her out.
        Some of his father’s contacts could help at this point but first he had to make it to the village and for that the wound needed dressing.
        But first, Joth was in desperate need of satiating his thirst.\n
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_2">Go to the well</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_2t">Joth made his way to the well limping and cursing from the pain on his sides. The well was no longer recognizable as it was half in flames.
        There seemed to be too many corpses floating in the water down below for the water to be in any drinking shape.
        No doubt excrement, urine, and blood made their way in causing the drinking water to be not only disgusting but also lethal if consumed.
        There was no sense in being hydrated now just to die of dysentery later.
        Part of Joth’s assassin training was to learn of all the pitfalls that awaited an assassin in the wild and drinking from contaminated sources would not help with that even though by this point he was desperate.</string>

    <string name="chapter_1_3">Search the corpses</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_3t">Suddenly it dawned on him that of the few corpses strewn around the courtyard, at least one should have a water bottle or two.
        Clan Grod Vim’s men were known to carry water and provisions so he tried to find soldiers of his clan hoping that the enemies had not pillaged the corpses long enough to strip their bare necessity unlike what they had done to all the weapons that were oddly missing from every corpse.\n\n

        The first water bottle was empty and the second one was punctured with all the fluid missing. Joth’s fate seemed sealed when a voice whispered:
        “Where is your sister boy?” Joth looked around and there lay his uncle with his back firmly against the wall as he was propping himself on a misshapen stick.
        Joth rushed to the old man’s aid but he had three arrows sticking out of his chest and firmly lodged in his ribs.
        He was no doubt bleeding inside and there was nothing Joth or any miracle worker or magician could do for his old uncle..\n\n

        “Did they take your sister, boy?” His uncle asked with a raspy voice though Joth was in awe of how the old man could muster enough strength for words.
        “You make your way to village then from there to town. In the town we have enough contacts to help you get your sister back.
        Elain may be strong, but if left there’s no telling what these animals will do to her in the long run. That being said you can’t rush it boy.
        You need a good few weeks to formulate a plan. Since you completed your training you should have a book with all our contacts inscribed in it. Go to those men and women and get help.
        Just remember not to trust anyone other than direct contacts. Not the Emperor and especially not that bastard of a Duke. These are all his men strewn about the place.
        Moving forward rely on your training, Joth! You may have no field experience but you were trained by the best. You are ready.”\n\n

        Joth nodded as tears began to roll down his cheeks.
        He might have been a Grod Vim but the sight of his old uncle drenched in blood and those arrows sticking out of him reminded him of losing his parents along with all his clan members and friends.
        This all was proving too much for the sixteen year old.\n\n

        “Calm down, boy! They may have taken us out but we killed them in numbers five times over. The Duke is reeling right now from the number of casualties.
        That’s why they left in such a hurry and only took the weapons and the gold with them instead of ransacking the whole place and removing all the valuables.
        By all rights I should be naked now as some fool of a mercenary or a regular guard lays claim to my armor.
        In the end we taught the bastards that the house of bows and daggers is not to be trifled with.” With that the old man patted Joth’s head and the boy forced a smile as his uncle let out a sad laugh.
        The crest of the family was that of bow and daggers and their banner was still waving over the compound. \n\n

        The old man’s weighty hand on Joth’s shoulder however forced him to let out a cry of pain as his wound was acting up . His uncle touched the side of his armor and noticed the puncture wound in the lining.
        The old man moved painfully as he handed Joth a bottle of water and Joth wasted no time in drinking from the bottle. “Gentle boy! Are you still bleeding?”\n\n

        Joth nodded and his uncle presented him with an option: “Well you have two options. First is to get a hot poker from the smithy.
        I know the smith kept them around as a crude and dirty way to close the wounds during the siege as the medicine ran dry. It’s going to hurt like no other.
        The burnt wound will leave an ugly scar and be a pain to heal and keep clean. The other option is some bandages and a needle and string to stitch the wound for now until you get some proper attention.
        Either you’ll pass out from the pain or scream and need moments to rest so you’d better act now so I can stand watch over you while I’m still alive.
        Both methods however need you to fetch a stick. Biting down on would divert from the pain.” \n\n

        Suddenly the old man grabbed Joth by the throat and pulled him close enough that Joth could smell the blood on his uncle.
        The old man gathered all his power and conviction and tried to reason with his nephew: “You… get your sister, Elain, and you get her to safety.
        Out there is the real world, boy. The real world has no time for heroics.
        You kill whoever you have to, even stab them in the back if forced to, and then you leave with your sister away from fighting and all the death.
        Forget me, your mother, or your father. We were killers and we knew the risk. If we didn’t die in this attack we’d die some other way.
        You save yourself and forget all about us. Just live boy…” \n\n

        Joth wanted to argue with the old man but deep down he knew that he was right. There was no time to waste.
        After Joth searched the yard he found a wooden spoon with a hefty handle and decided that it just had to do.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_4a">Cauterize the wound</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_4at">It was not too hard to find the poker and Joth soon came back to his uncle.
        Joth had to wait a while for the poker to cool down from the red hot temperature otherwise he could seriously burn himself and that would bring greater harm than good.
        The old man advised Joth to cover the spoon with some fabric and then bite down to divert Joth’s attention from pain.
        The pain of the burning flesh was unbearable and Joth passed out after screaming from the bottom of his soul.
        The smell of burning flesh was lost in the smell of death that covered the yard and surrounded other dead bodies.
        The last image he remembered was that of his uncle’s sad and concerned look.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_4b">Stitch the wound</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_4bt">It took a while for Joth to find a needle and some thread.
        As luck would have it the needle was a bit think for stitching work which spelled a great deal of pain but beggars could hardly be choosers.
        The old man advised Joth to cover the spoon with some fabric and then bite down in order to divert Joth’s attention from pain.
        The pain of each stab at Joth’s flesh was unbearable and yet Joth prevailed though he screamed from the bottom of his soul every time the needle met flesh.
        By the time he was done, Joth was ready for a break to let the wound set before walking around so he sat and closed his eyes before removing the fabric from his mouth.
        The last image he remembered was that of his uncle’s sad and concerned look.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_4st">As he awoke to silence, Joth spat out the fabric and with it the spoon and cursed once or twice before getting a bearing of his surroundings.\n\n

        His uncle was hunched over him watching him the entire time.
        However, as Joth stood the old man’s eyes remained fixated on the ground instead of following Joth to his feet.
        Joth knew that there was no time to waste on sentimentalities and yet a good few tears left his eyes and his nose began to run.
        The old man was always a friend to him and now he was no more. Joth’s eyes took a semblance of anger to them and yet the tears kept on flowing.
        He closed the old man’s eyes and draped him in one of the last half decent flags of the Grod Vim clan.
        When the old man was draped in the flag of the two daggers and a bow, Joth kissed him on his forehead as a last sign of goodbye and an attribute to the elder before leaving him to meet the family elders in the molten hills of afterlife.\n\n

        The fortress had a solemn look about it. It was a dark and dingy night but through the dense darkness Joth could feel the grip of death.
        The assassins had fought a mighty battle here. Many had died here and at one glance there were far more of the enemy than that of the assassins.
        The problem was that the clan could not afford to lose this many skilled lives while the Duke’s men could have easily raised many more armies.
        The breeze was picking up the stench of rotting corpses and Joth knew that he had to move fast. He had to use what was left of night to find safety.
        The day would strip any possible cover the young man might have and make him a target for every guard or patrol out there.
        His only chance of survival was to blend in with the crowd. Otherwise, he would easy to spot and with his wound Joth stood no chance of outrunning anyone.\n\n

        Joth decided to say a final prayer to grant all the fallen from his clan safe passage to afterlife before embarking down the only path down this mountain.
        The road was well made and even a testament to the wealth and importance of the Grod Vim clan. The night was a decent cover and the path would take Joth to a nearby village.
        This village was quaint little place in shadow of the mountain that housed the clan’s refuge.
        Though the village was named Sacred Stone after the sacred stone that was placed in its only square, it was called the Grod Vim village fondly as it was the last refuge for anyone who wished to climb the mountain and meet Joth’s infamous clan.
        Most people would arrive at the village and stay anywhere from a night to a month before climbing just to steel their nerves and make sure they could face the famed grim assassins of Grod Vim mountain.
        The clan of assassins was the best thing that happened to the village and the villagers were well aware of that.
        This meant that many of the villagers were sympathetic to the Grod Vim clan but separated enough from the clan’s structure to be spared from the purge.
        If Joth could make it down the mountain then he was sure to find shelter with some of the more trusted villagers before sitting out to find the clan’s contacts or safehouse.\n\n

        Joth was almost lost to his plans and figuring out a method to get vengeance when a loud roaring laughter brought him to his senses.
        There was a bright light of a campfire that was a beacon in the middle of this dark night and somehow Joth managed to miss it as he was lost in thought despite all its splendor.
        The campfire managed to cast to all the dark surrounds highlighting two figures. Both were armored with a kettle helm and a gambeson.
        One of the men who was standing watch by the path with the intent to block it was carrying a long spear while his sword remained in its scabbard.
        The other fellow was laying by the campfire with his back to the road. He had a shield and a sword and he was resting, waiting for his shift.
        The pair were laughing after that exchange but Joth knew that they were the remnants of murderers who attacked his clan.
        Judging by the number of the guards posted here the Duke’s men felt that they had done a thorough job as they were not worried about survivors.
        The unlucky two were all that stood between Joth and the village.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_5a">Get off the path and sneak past</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_5at">Joth squats down to keep closer to the ground and begins to leave the gravel paved path.
        A few moments after he encircled the enemy camp his foot hits a plated rock in the uneven grass.
        The sudden stop made the %1$s wound on Joth’s side to act up and searing pulses of pain spread across Joth’s body jolting his brain.
        Faced with all that pain the young man let out a muffled scream of pain. Sadly, he had no time to dwell on it when the first guard called: “Who goes there?”
        The other guard was now up and they were both looking into the darkness to find any sign of movement.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_5b">How dare they block my path</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_5bt">Joth now draws the very same dagger that was used to stab him  during the battle and he stands in the darkness before letting out a scream and charging the young guard.
        The young man is startled but has enough time to lower his spear and block Joth’s advance before his friend joins him with a raised shield and a drawn blade.
        “What is this? Some strangler puppy out to join his ancestors in the pits of death? You made a big mistake boy. You belong in the shadows.
        Out in the light there is two of us and one of you.” \n\n

        Joth raises his dagger and bypasses the tip of the spear to even out the odds. As luck would have it the young guard uses his spear like a staff and bashes it to Joth’s side.
        The deep cut on the side opens and blood gushes out as Joth begins flailing for a moment of reprieve.
        The other guard moves in and blocks Joth’s dagger with his shield before pushing Joth’s dagger to the side and stabbing at Joth’s Neck.
        “You did well kid!” Says the guard to his younger comrade. Joth thinks of his father, his mother, and of Elian who was now surely lost.
        “Rest in peace” is what the older guard says before driving his blade home and delivering mercy. \n\n

        YOU DIED
    </string>


    <string name="chapter_1_6a">Remain Silent</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_6a_preT">Joth remained silent and frozen in his place.
        Moments felt like hours as the two guards scanned the darkness for anything that might stand out.
        “Are you sure you saw something, boy? Or is this another one of your tricks?” Asked the guard from his friend. \n\n

        “I swear on all that is holy… I heard something and there could have been some movement.
        Maybe I should check?” The younger guard asked his more seasoned companion.\n\n

       “Wait up boy…” The old man extended his arm to prevent the young man from charging into the darkness.
        “Maybe it is the ghost of all them assassins coming back at night to haunt us for our attack. After all the bastards were a creepy bunch.
        For all we know that lot found a way to come back to life. I mean…”\n\n

        “Shut up you old fool! Your silly stories of ghosts and demons are wearing thin these days.
        I mean they were funny at first but now I’ve had just about enough…”
        The young man tried to come and investigate but the older guard stopped him again.\n\n

        “Calm down boy before you get yourself killed. What if it is a surviving assassin?
        You’re going to get killed in the darkness and I will be left to fend for myself. Let’s say you heard this noise and saw the movement.
        What says it wasn’t some tiny little critter making all the noise. For all you know the little devil is gone by now.
        Take it from me, when it’s dark trees and bushes and all manner of animals come to life. Night is creepy everywhere but specially around these parts.
        Now if you want to be a guard and thrive you need friends. Screaming bloody murder every time you hear a suspicious noise is going to make you very unpopular fast.
        I say we wait and see if there is more movement before we investigate. There’s no sense in getting killed out here when the army has moved out.”
        The older guard nods and the younger one nods back as the older one goes back to lying down.
        After a few moments Joth begins to move  but takes him time as he is now aware of his wound.
        He makes his way around the camp without a hitch and soon he is back on the path and distancing himself from the pair as fast as he can.\n\n

        Joth gets to the outskirts of the village. His</string>

    <string name="chapter_1_6a_uCa">&#160;cauterized&#160;</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_6a_uCb">&#160;stitched&#160;</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_6a_postT">wound was acting up by now.
        He could feel some fluid running down his body and yet the village and an alchemist were so close that Joth suppressed all feelings of pain and disgust just to get closer to the village.
        The village had a short wall protecting its surroundings.
        It was more to mark the edge of the village than a defensive structure and it could never protect the villagers from a determined army but against small raids and local bandits, this structure could serve a vital purpose.
        Two side paths on the other side of the wall were lit to serve as a guide for any travelers, to ward off against wild animals, and to warn the bandits that the village guards was vigilant.
        To make it to old man Holgon.  He was the village alchemist and he did some work for the clan so Joth trusted him.
        The old man Holgon was also famed? Joth and Elain used to talk to the old man and learn a great deal about alchemy from the old man.\n\n

        But what stood in front of Joth was a dimly lit street and a young guard wielding spear and sporting the Duke’s colors.
        Had it been a local guard Joth was fairly sure he would be able to convince the guard to let him through but the Duke’s men were not to be reasoned with.
        The guard was armed with a spear. He was hugging the spear and looked tired. Joth could see him doze off every now and then.
        If rushed the guard would probably see Joth approaching but Joth doubted the fellow would be capable to react in time.
        Luckily, unlike the other two guards back in the camp this man was alone and in his current state Joth was confident he could take on a single opponent.\n\n

        Just as Joth was planning his method of approach the man dozed off.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_6b">Attack the first guard while there is still a chance</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_6bt">Joth now draws the very same dagger that was used to stab him  during the battle and charges the young guard.
        Despite having a spear, the guard was slow to react until Joth was upon him.
        When he stabbed the guard in his unprotected neck, Joth looked into his face now lit by the campfire.
        It was a boy no older than Joth. No wonder he was slow to react. This could very well have been his first post.
        Blood came running out of the boy’s mouth and Joth withdrew his dagger and a rainbow of blood erupted from the boy’s jugular dancing to the beats of his heart.
        By now the other guard was up and ready with his shield at the ready and his sword raised high.\n\n

        “What a shame! I know his father. Poor boy was sweet on a local girl.
        No wonder the Duke eradicated you demons…” Joth tried a fast attack towards the man’s face as he raised the shield and stabbed with his right hand.
        Joth tried to block the guard’s straight blade with the back of his blade but this old man was quite skilled.
        Joth could have matched the man any other day but his side wound was gushing blood by now.
        In a fit of rage Joth screamed in pain and masked himself behind the guard’s shield before stabbing the man in his neck.
        The guard however instinctively raised his shield and stabbed at Joth.
        Normally Joth would have been able to easy dodge such a last futile effort but this was no normal injury.
        The guard’s blade pierced Joth’s abdomen and forced him to his knees.
        Joth tried to muster his strength and walk into the darkness but he knew that he would not make it to the Village.
        He drew the blade out and sat in darkness bleeding. His last thought was of Elian and the clan of daggers and bow.\n\n

        YOU DIED
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_7a">Rush the guard and press the advantage</string>
    <string name="chapter_1_7a_preT">Joth took off running towards the wall and climb over it before the middle-aged guard awoke from the commotion.
        Before he could level his spear Joth rushed in close to where he could hear the fellow breathing.
        Joth sliced at the man’s neck before jabbing the blade into his neck.  The man bled and fell into Joth’s arms.
        He should hid the body away from the village but Joth was worried about his wound and there was no possible way he could get rid of the body in such a short time.
        Old man Holgon would not appreciate Joth showing up with a body even though he probably had the chemicals to get rid of the body after a few weeks.
        Joth lifted the body threw it over the wall in hopes that by the time the body is discovered he is hidden or gone from the village.
        He returned and tried hard to mix the blood into the dirt to hid any signs of struggle.
        Some blood had gotten on the wall and so Joth covered it with some dirt.\n\n

        Joth made his way to a back alley where the backdoor to the alchemy shop was located.
        Old man Holgon was dedicated to his work and used to live on the second floor of his shop ever since his wife passed away and his daughters married city folk.
        His daughters were red headed just like Elian which was why the old grumpy man was kind to her and brough her on as an apprentice.
        Joth knocked lightly fearful of attracting attention.
        A creaking sound could be heard moments later as well as the roaring voice of Old man Holgon cursing and complain that “whoever you are, you better be dying or I’ll kill you myself.”
        The loud sound of a latch opening jolted the fearful Joth when the old man opened the door saying:
        “Do you have any idea what time…” The old man was carrying an oil lamp when his eyes locked to Joth’s eyes and the boy and the man stared at one another in disbelief.
        The old man grabbed Joth by the arm and pulled him in quiet violently as Joth reeled from the pain of his wound.
        The old man noticed the unnatural twitch and saw the gash in Joth’s garment but he moved to the window and began scanning the neighborhood.
        “Have you lost your mind? If one of my neighbors saw you then we’ll both be dead by tomorrow.
        Did you kill anyone to get here? Are they searching for you? Do they even know you’re alive?”\n\n

        “I had to kill one of the Duke’s men. I threw the body overt the wall. I am wounded old man!”\n\n

        “I can see that! Well this just mean they’ll come looking for you so you need to lay low until your wounds heal.”
        He gestured to Joth to remove his shirt and without missing a beat asked: “Where is that red headed menace of a sister of yours? Did… make it ?”\n\n

        Joth removed his shirt and nodded at the same time. There was some blood coming from the wound.
        “Her grandfather took her away during the invasion. My dad was worried for her.”  Joth fished his words worried about the state of his wound.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_7a_uCa">“You burned yourself you silly little fool!
        Yes, the heat can seal the wound but it can open the body to deadly miasma and infection you idiot.
        It’ll take three weeks to seal the wound properly and make sure you’re in a fighting condition.
        Next time you decided to burn yourself think first and then act.
        The good news is that whoever did that to you missed your kidneys judging by the trajectory of the wound and the fact that you are still standing.
        You also managed to burn your kidneys so that is good.  Either way I have to work overtime to put you back together.”\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_7a_uCb">“You stitched yourself without cleaning the wound first?
        It was good thinking to sew the wound but both the wound and the equipment needs to be heated and doused with potion to insure the deadly miasma does not cause an infection.
        I guess you can’t be choosy in the field of battle but still one should try.
        It’ll take three weeks to seal the wound properly and make sure you’re in a fighting condition.
        The good news is that whoever did that to you missed your kidneys judging by the trajectory of the wound and the fact that you are still standing.
        You did a fine job stitching yourself even though I can see signs of you flinching.
        Still you seemed to have kept the stitches pretty neat.
        Either way I have to work overtime to put you back together.”\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_7a_postT">“You can have one of the patient’s beds down in the basement. How are you paying for all this?”
        Asked the old man before he saw a worried look in Joth’s eyes. “Don’t worry about the pay. It’s all on me.
        You just get better and get that crazy tomboy half-sister of yours from her grandfather and we can call it all even.
        Taking care of your sister is the closest I’ve come to having a son. She is a handful.
        If you sit back her grandfather might let go of her once he realizes what he’s gotten himself into with that little dragon.”
        Both Joth and the old man burst into laughter and Joth’s wound hurt with each laughter.\n\n
    </string>

    <string name="chapter_1_7b">Wait and asses the surroundings before challenging the man to a fair fight </string>
    <string name="chapter_1_7bt">There wasn’t a soul to be seen around other than a local bird that nearly gave Joth the fright of his life.
        Joth observed the surroundings and decided it was time to strike. The guard eventually woke and he saw Joth rushing the walls.
        Joth made it over when the panicking man screamed “intruder” at the top of his lungs.
        Joth managed to close in with the screaming guard and dispatch him when he felt the footsteps of other soldiers.
        As he pulled his dagger out of the guard’s neck, an archer from a commanding wooden tower let loosed an arrow that pierced Joth’s shoulder.
        The tower was close and Joth rushed toward it but soon he was faced with a wall of spears and shields.
        Joth could not charge into the deadly wall when another arrow from an archer on a rooftop behind him caught the bough right between his shoulder blades.
        Joth fell to the ground but the wall of spears did not break. They wait for the archers to let arrows loose again.\n\n

        YOU DIED
    </string>

</resources>
